A Guide to the Letters of Katherine Anne Porter, 1937-1961
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Katherine Anne Porter 1937-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6339-a
This collection consists of 11 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1966 Feb 23.
Contents List
- Letters
  - Katherine Anne Porter, New Orleans, to John H. [Birss], New York, New York [1937 Dec 15], TLS, 2 p.
    [Includes autograph notes by both correspondents; lists Porter's published works; comments on upcoming publication of Pale Horse, Pale Rider, [Barrett] Wendell's biography of Cotton Mather and his involvement in the Salem witchcraft trials.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, New York, New York, to Mr. Armitage 1950 Nov 7, TLS, 1 p.
    [Comments on [Ezra] "Pound question" and humankind's tendency to periodically "groval in the wallow"; describes the passing-on of culture of her pioneer ancestors and the necessity to defend it in order to live in freedom.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, [Ann Arbor, Michigan], to H. H. Rappaport, Brooklyn, New York 1954 Apr 13, ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for the gift of a much-read copy of one of her books and for the "good human impulse that brought it here."]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, [Ann Arbor, Michigan], to H. A. Rappaport, Brooklyn, New York 1954 May 12, ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses recent picture; comments on his and his wife's health; expresses appreciation of gift of book.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, Brussels, Belgium, to H. A. Rappaport, Brooklyn, New York 1955 Feb 8, ALS, 3 p. w/env
    [Apologizes for delay in writing due to work at the University of Michigan, lectures in the United States, preparation for a year in Europe as a Fullbright lecturer, a holiday in England, Rome and Paris, and illness of several weeks from which she is recovering; describes Brussels, where she is headquartered; thanks him for gift of Flowering Judas.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, North Woods, Connecticut, to Mr. and Mrs. H. A. Rappaport, Brooklyn, New York 1955 Dec [14], ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks them for gift of new edition of "a [bright particular faith ?]"; calls attention to the homemade card.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, Southbury, to Clifton Waller Barrett 1957 Nov 19, ALS, 1 p.
    [Hopes he will see her play which will open in early December at the Jan Hus Auditorium "God willing"; compares the uncertainty of theater to the "Safe Harbor" of writing.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter, Southbu[ry], to Waller and Cornelia Barrett, New York, New York 1957 Dec, ANS, 1 p.
    [Sends best wishes for the holidays.]
  - Katherine Anne Porter to Monroe Wheeler 1960 Dec 27, transcript, 3 p.
    [Excerpts of a letter discussing her love for him; contrasts to clingy demanding love of others she has experienced; refers to her writing, her wealth of ideas, most of which are over 25 years old; discusses the process of writing "Flowering Judas," difficulty of communicating this approach to students; mentions working on 2 stories one of which is "Vision of Heaven by Fra Angelico."]
  - Clifton Waller Barrett to Monroe Wheeler, New York, New York 1961 Feb 13, TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Thanks him for excerpts of letter from Katherine Anne Porter dated December 27, 1960.]
- Photograph
  - Katherine Anne Porter, head and shoulders 1954 May 12, [Autographed.] Photo